var QuestionsJson = [{
  "question": "What is the NetPromoter method?",
  "answer": "The ‘how likely are you to recommend this to a friend” method. Does not really help us as UX researchers."
},
{
  "question": "Name two possible Usability Goals",
  "answer": "Learnable, Memorable, Flexible: Multiple ways to accomplish tasks, Efficient: Perform tasks quickly, Pleasing: High subjective. Robust: Good feedback so user can recover, Out of box experience: First time to “oh that’s cool”, Fun, Enjoyable"
},
{
  "question": "What is the Iterative Design Method?",
  "answer": "Short cycles of design, prototype, evaluation"
},
{
  "question": "What are slips?",
  "answer": "Mistakes with the right goal, Wrong action. very common. Typos and automatic behaviours."
},
{
  "question": "Mode error is a type of _______ error.",
  "answer": "Slip."
},
{
  "question": "What is a Quasimode error?",
  "answer": "Active application as long as the user is performing a conscious action, e.g., keeping a key pressed."
},
{
  "question": "Name two types of slip errors",
  "answer":"Capture errors: Frequently done activity takes over. Description/Similarity Slip: Ex. Flipping wrong switch. Data-driven errors: Ex. Call a secretary to reserve a room, dial room number. Associative activation: Ex. Office phone rings, but say “come in”. Loss of activation:"
},
{
  "question": "What is a capture error?",
  "answer":"A type of slip error where a frequently done action takes over."
},
{
  "question": "Name two types of data collection methods for diary studies and experience sampling.",
  "answer":"interval-based: record data at a particular time each day, signal-based: record when told to. Event-based: record after a specified event."
},
{
  "question": "What is triangulation?",
  "answer":"The use of multiple approaches to converge and confirm emerging findings. Methods: Multiple-sources, multiple-methods, multiple-investigators, multiple theories."
},
{
  "question": "What is a design pattern?",
  "answer":"Proven designs that can be reused to satisfy design problems with good solutions."
},
{
  "question": "What are some differences between pattern and guidelines?",
  "answer":"Patterns tend to be more specific. Guidlines offer higher-level information. Patterns tend to be nouns/tangible things (ex. Nav bar)."
},
{
  "question": "The DOM is Static. True or False?",
  "answer":"False."
},
{
  "question": "How are GUIs roughly organized?",
  "answer":"WIMP: Windows, Icons, Menus, Pointers"
},
{
  "question": "Name 2 terms for highly reusable interactive components.",
  "answer":"Widgets, controls, components, interactors."
},
{
  "question": "What is event-driven programming?",
  "answer":"Input from user is handled as events."
},
{
  "question": "What are the advantages of the MVC model?",
  "answer":"Loose coupling, separation of concerns, reusable. Useful for organizing at a small scale (widgets) and large scale. many frameworks also follow these guidelines."
},
{
  "question": "Describe the gulf of evaluation.",
  "answer":"It is the gap between the user's understanding of how the system works vs. how the system actually works."
},
{
  "question": "What is the Human Processor model?",
  "answer":"Sees the human as an information processor. Perceptual system, motor system, cognitive system."
},
{
  "question": "About what percent of males and females are color blind?",
  "answer":"about 8% of men and .05% of women."
},
{
  "question": "What are two types of memories (cognitive processors)?",
  "answer":"Short term memory + Long term memory"
},
{
  "question": "What are three ways to improve Fitts law",
  "answer":"Placing buttons on sides makes it infinite width and thus easier to hit. Larger labels are easier to hit. Spacing between icons make them easier to hit. Avoid pointing tasks altogether: Keyboard shortcuts, Mouse Wheel, Snapping"
},
{
  "question": "Every System has Three Different Mental Models. What are they?",
  "answer":"Design Model - How you, the designer, intend the system to work. System Image - Your Implementation. User Model - How users think the system works"
},
{
  "question": "What are affordances?",
  "answer":"Clues to their operation that are readily apparent. Often visual."
},
{
  "question": "Give an example of mapping controls.",
  "answer":"Ex: Stove top. How do we map the buttons to the stove? Maybe the stoves are not in a 2 by 2 grid. Instead the are in a single row. Buttons are directly below. The mapping is clear: users clearly know which buttons control what stovetop."
},
{
  "question": "Why are metaphors sometimes not the best visualization technique",
  "answer":"Metaphor may be depreciated(ex. floppy disk) or too literal (ex. I-books previous UI)."
},
{
  "question": "What is a Skeuomorphic Interface?",
  "answer":"graphical user interface designed to describe interface objects that mimic their real-world counterparts(metaphors)."
},
{
  "question": "Name 3 interaction techniques.",
  "answer": "Pointing tasks, Text input, Voice input, touch, tilting."
},
{
  "question": "Name 2 output techniques.",
  "answer": "Zooming. Overlays. Detail inspection."
},
{
  "question": "How quick does something need to be to feel like 'instant response'?",
  "answer": "100ms."
},
{
  "question": "What is a good and bad response time?",
  "answer": "2 seconds = good. 10-15 = bad."
},
{
  "question": "How much faster does your site need to be to have an advantage over competiters?",
  "answer": "250 ms."
},
{
  "question": "What is REST?",
  "answer": "REpresentational State Transfer (REST). Describes architectural style of the web, i.e., describes the systems on a high-level."
},
{
  "question": "Name the steps to a user study with regards to ethical concerns.",
  "answer": "You must alleviate stress. Avoid pressuring the participant. Let them know they can quit. Anonymize data."
},
{
  "question": "Name the steps to a user study.",
  "answer": "Describe the purpose. Tell them you are testing the product, not them. Tell them they can quit anytime. Demonstrate how to use equipment. Explain how to do a think aloud. Explain you will not provide help. Explain basic concept of UI. Describe the task."
},
{
  "question": "What does light travel through in the human eye?",
  "answer": "cornea →crystalline lens →retina"
},
{
  "question": "What does the iris do in the human eye?",
  "answer": "It controls the amount of light that passes through"
},
{
  "question": "What does the optic nerve do?",
  "answer": "Transfers processed light to the visual cortex"
},
{
  "question": "What is the Fovea?",
  "answer": "Center of the retina. Has the most cones"
},
{
  "question": "What is the Value of the a color?",
  "answer": "describes overall intensity to how light or dark a color is.It is the only dimension of color that may exist by itself."
},
{
  "question": "What does Don Norman say, in the first chapter of his book, are the most important characteristics of good design?",
  "answer": "Discoverability and understandability."
},
{
  "question": "What does brushing and linking mean?",
  "answer": "Brushing is selecting subset of Data. Linking means showing how the data behaves in each plot based on the filter applied by brushing"
},
{
  "question": "What are parrallel coordinate charts typically used for?",
  "answer": "High-dimentional data."
},
{
  "question": "What are benefits to using animations in your GUI?",
  "answer": "Animations can reinforce mental models. Make transitions less jarring. Increases appeal. Provides visual continuity. Pre-action affordances. Post-action feedback."
},
{
  "question": "What is the principal of Solidity?",
  "answer": "Make objects appear to be solid(by using principals squash and Stretch, motion blur, arrivals and departures(Rather than simply appearing or disappearing, have smooth easing on and off the screen)"
},
{
  "question": "What is the principal of Exaggeration?",
  "answer": "Exaggerate certain actions to enhance perception by using the Anitcipation principal( small counter movement just prior to the main movement). "
},
{
  "question": "What is the principal of Reinforcement?",
  "answer": "Effects to drive home feeling of reality such as Slow in and slow out, Arcs, and Follow through(Loosely tied parts should continue moving after the character has stopped)."
},
{
  "question": "What is the medical model of disability?",
  "answer": "Implies Disability is the responsibility of individuals. Relies solely on medical systems to provide access. Historically used to justify extremes."
},
{
  "question": "What is the social model of disability?",
  "answer": "Responsibility of society to adapt to be accessible. Ignores the relationship between health, disease, and disability. Separates different types of disability based on barrier."
},
{
  "question": "What is the Identity and Diversity Model of disability?",
  "answer": "Embraces Disability as a Complex (good and bad) lived experience. A bit of both social and medical models"
},
{
  "question": "What is Machine learning?",
  "answer": "Algorithms that are good at recognizing patterns in large amounts of data. Subfield of AI getting most attention due to big advances."
},
{
  "question": "What is the Identity and Diversity Model of disability?",
  "answer": "Embraces Disability as a Complex (good and bad) lived experience. A bit of both social and medical models"
},
{
  "question": "What are some 'bad words' for disability??",
  "answer": "Handicapped, ‘cripple’ or ‘crip’, ‘suffering from / victim of ...’, ‘deficient’/ ‘deviant’, ‘Wheelchair bound’, ‘epileptics’, ‘diabetics’, etc."
},
{
  "question": "Accessibility is not _________",
  "answer": "Usability."
},
{
  "question": "What are some DOs of accessible design?",
  "answer": "Make Accessibility a constant priority. Include disabled people in the design process. Compensate accordingly."
},
{
  "question": "What are some DONTs of accessible design?",
  "answer": "Assume disabled people can’t use your technology. Simulate disability. Only Use standards as a checklist. Rely on expensive accommodations."
},
{
  "question": "What are Assistive Technologies?",
  "answer": "products, equipment, and systems that enhance learning, working, and daily living for persons with disabilities. "
},
{
  "question": "What are some assistive technologies for different areas of disabilities?",
  "answer": "Visual - Screen Readers. Auditory - Captions, Sign Language interpretation. Motor - Eye trackers, adaptive buttons. Cognitive - Simple language, consistent navigation, color choice, symbols."
},
{
  "question": "What is Section 508?",
  "answer": "Section 508 of the US Rehabilitation Act (1973) requires all electronic and info technologies purchased by the U.S. govt  to be accessible. Includes web sites used by the Federal govt "
},
{
  "question": "What are the 4 principles of the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG)?",
  "answer": "Perceivable. Operable. Understandable. Robust."
},
{
  "question": "What is the Text Equivalence Concept?",
  "answer": "Accompany as much of your Web content—including images, audio, and movies—with plain text, since text is highly accessible"
},
{
  "question": "How do you evaluate the effectiveness of machine learning algorithms?",
  "answer": "1) Mean Absolute Error + Mean Squared Error. <br>2) Confusion Matrix. <br>3) accuracy- what did we get right? <br>4) Precision - how many of predicted true was actually true <br>5) Recall - focus on actual positives over predicted positives.(Probability of prediction)<br>6) ROC Curve"
},
{
  "question": "What are advantages to machine learning?",
  "answer": "Addresses the problem of too much data. Offers solutions to longstanding hard problems. Enables new kinds of UX. Potential for reducing human bias. Increased accuracy. Process big data."
},
{
  "question": "What is the 5-step approuch to machine learning?",
  "answer": "Step 1: Get lots of data <br> Step 2: Figure out useful features <br>Step 3: Select and train the ML algorithm<br>Step 4: Evaluate metrics (and iterate)<br>Step 5: Deploy"
},
{
  "question": "What are 2 classes of machine learning algorithms?",
  "answer": "1. Supervised algorithms - You have ground truth labels (e.g. spam vs ham)<br>2. Unsupervised algorithms - Typically clustering things together. Generally, unsupervised harder, active area of research."
},
{
  "question": "What is regression as it relates to machine learning?",
  "answer": "Predicting a continuous value based on inputs (example: house price based on bedrooms, bathrooms, square footage, etc."
},
{
  "question": "What is classification as it relates to machine learning?",
  "answer": "Predicting from a set of categories. (Ex: Spam vs Ham?). Lots of variants"
},
{
  "question": "Decision Trees and (Support Vector Machine)SVMs are two examples of ___________",
  "answer": "Supervised classifiers"
},
{
  "question": "What is 'overfitting'?",
  "answer": "When your ML model is too specific for the data you have. ML model tuned too much to work well for your data, may not work for real-world data. This is one of the most common problems for ML. Bad for the generalizability of your results, cross validation is a common technique to mitigate"
},
{
  "question": "What are some ways to avoid 'overfitting' in ML models?",
  "answer": "Train model on training set, and test on test set. Often does through cross validation. 5-fold cross validation - train on everything except 1 set of data."
},
{
  "question": "When evaluating the effectiveness of your ML model, what is Prior Probabilities?",
  "answer": "Probability before any observations (i.e. just guessing). Your trained model needs to do better than prior."
},
{
  "question": "What are some tools to help Evaluate Effectiveness of an ML model?",
  "answer": "1. Mean Absolute Error / Mean Squared Error <br>2. Accuracy<br>3. False positives / False negatives<br>4. Precision / Recall<br>5. Confusion matrix<br>6. Receiver Operating Characteristic (ROC)."
},
{
  "question": "What is a Confusion Matrix?",
  "answer": "A huge table of positive and negative predictions and results. Has all the data listed. Used to assess Accuracy, Precision, and recall."
},
{
  "question": "What is a ROC curve?",
  "answer": "Reciever Operating Characteristic. Used to Assess Recall and false positive rate. You'll want to have a curve that goes stright up and curves to the right."
},
{
  "question": "What is recall a good metric for?",
  "answer": "When it is ok to get some false positives but harder to recieve false negatives (example: Cancer diagnosis)"
},
{
  "question": "What is accuracy a good metric for?",
  "answer": "When it is ok to get some false positives and false negatives but want to prioritize getting true positives and negatives"
},
{
  "question": "What is precision a good metric for?",
  "answer": "When it is ok to get some false negatives but harder to recieve false positives"
},
{
  "question": "What are some ways to label large datasets?",
  "answer": "Crowdsource. Machine Turks. Get users to label things for you. Get data as a side effect of things users already do (example: likes, captcha, search engine clicks). Make it fun or meaningful."
},
{
  "question": "What are first 11 guidelines for Human-AI Interaction?",
  "answer": "1) Make clear what the system can do<br>2) Make clear how well the system can do what it can do<br>3) Time Services Based on Context(ex. clippy)<br>4) Show Contextually Relevant Info<br>5) Match Relevant Social Norms<br>6) Mitigate Social Biases<br>7) Support Efficient Invocation<br>8) Support Efficient Dismissal<br>9)Support Efficient Correction<br>10) Scope Services When in Doubt<br>11) Make Clear Why System Did What it Did"
},
{
  "question": "What is Information Visualization?",
  "answer": "The use of computer-supported, interactive visual representations of data to amplify cognition."
},
{
  "question": "What is an appropriate use of color in Information Visualization?",
  "answer": "When mapping colors, better to modify saturation and value vs hue (in HSV). A red flag is rainbow colors. "
},
{
  "question": "What are some variables you can manipulate in data viz?",
  "answer": "Size, Value, Orientation, Texture, Shape, Position (2D / 3D)"
},
{
  "question": "What are some uses of info viz?",
  "answer": "Exploratory: Help us analyze and reason. <br>Explanatory: Help explain or persuade others. <br>Aesthetics"
},
{
  "question": "All visualizations have ________",
  "answer": "Tradeoffs (example: election maps)"
},
{
  "question": "What are some tools to help focus + context(allocate the pixels on the screen in the most meaningful way) in info viz?",
  "answer": "TableLens, DateLens, Fisheye Views"
},
{
  "question": "What are are characteristics of unuseful info viz?",
  "answer": "Data blob: too much granular info. Viz that are misread(hurricane maps). Unneeded information (towing sign)"
},
{
  "question": "What are are characteristics of BAD info viz?",
  "answer": "Axises don't start at 0. Axis skips years/ counts with no indication that it is doing so. Too many keys to remember. 3D visualizations. Rainbow spectrum"
},
{
  "question": "What are are characteristics of GOOD info viz?",
  "answer": "Values sorted from greatest to least or vice versa. Pick good scales."
},
{
  "question": "What is a problem with Multidimensional Data in info viz?",
  "answer": "You cannot plot it easily using standard charts like bar charts."
},
{
  "question": "What is FATE?",
  "answer": "Fairness Accountability Transparency Ethics. Bias in a system is an often hidden ethical issue."
},
{
  "question": "What are some Possible Sources of Harmful Biases in machine learning?",
  "answer": "How data was collected / sampled. Bias in the data itself. Reflects biases that exist in society. Blindspots of the product team (“Unknown unknowns”). Categories you choose for your system."
},
{
  "question": "What are 2 types of harmful biases?",
  "answer": "1) Allocative Harms - Resources are allocated unfairly<br>2) Representational Harms - Promotes offensive / negative views of a group."
},
{
  "question": "What are 5 types of Representational Harms?",
  "answer": "1) Stereotypes <br>2) Recognition(computers can't understand people who aren't white)<br>3) Denigration(ex: labelling black people as apes)<br>4) Under-representation<br>5) Exnomination - Implicitly making something the 'norm', which can reinforce power"
},
{
  "question": "What are some good graphics techniques for presentations?",
  "answer": "Cropping well. Be sparse. Matting(removal of BG). Camera angle. Charts(avoid busy ones, however). Labels (on photos, graphs, etc). Line drawings. Uniformity (make a stencil). Consistent overlays."
},
{
  "question": "What is Abstraction?",
  "answer": "Reducing the information content of a concept or an observable phenomenon, typically to retain only information which is relevant for a particular purpose."
},
{
  "question": "What are top reasons start-ups fail?",
  "answer": "Failure to pivot, Bad leadership, No market need (build something no one cares about), Run out of cash, Market need and running out of cash go hand in hand, Poor product, Ignore customers"
},
{
  "question": "Describe the 5 factors in the Diffusion of Innovations",
  "answer": "Relative Advantage(How much better over what already exists?)<br>Trialability(How easy is it to try?)<br>Complexity(How difficult/confusing is it?)<br>Compatibility(How well fits into person’s needs, usage, beliefs)<br>Observability(Easy to see others gaining value)"
},
{
  "question": "About what percent of the world has a disability?",
  "answer": "13%"
}];


function generateRandomIndex(maxIndex){
      return Math.floor(Math.random() * maxIndex);
  }
function generateRandomQuestion(){
    let index = generateRandomIndex(QuestionsJson.length);
    return QuestionsJson[index];
}



function onLoad() {
    var QandA = generateRandomQuestion();
    // fill in code
    console.log(QandA.answer);
    document.getElementById("question").innerHTML = QandA.question;
    document.getElementById("answer").style.color = "white";
    document.getElementById("answer").innerHTML = QandA.answer;
  }
  function showAnswer() {
    document.getElementById("answer").style.color = "black";
  }